In this clip we're going to show you how to do side lying abduction.
There's standing and then side lying abduction for the outer thigh, which is just an extension of the glute in your rear behind you.
It's not a separate muscle so you're still working behind but we're going to focus on the outside lateral aspect of the thigh.
Bringing and stacking our hips, you've got an elbow right underneath the shoulder joint, nice square core, we don't want anything else to move.
Now if you want to you can come all the way down and rest your head on your arm and we lift, exhale, inhale, down.
We exhale on contraction, which that's the contraction phase on the lift and your forcing that energy, shooting it right out through your heal and release.
Exhale, inhale, exhale, inhale.
Now of course you can do this without tubing and get that down pat and then add in variable resistance, depending on the thickness of the tubing, will depend on how tight the resistance is and how quickly you'll become fatigued.
So contract and release, keeping both knees bent and you always have the option for balance purpose to bend your bottom knee if you wish for more stability and then less of a balance challenge for you.
Ten to fifteen reps, three sets.